

# **Javad Adib**







# Full Stack PHP Developer, Software Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. Build 7+ infrastructure of multi-million dollar scalable projects from scratch. Earn valuable knowledge via collaboration with specialists. A learner who knows how to learn. Interested in negotiating and comprehending the customer. Extensive wisdom from eCommerce. Open-source enthusiast.

🔀 mr.javad.adib@gmail.com

+98-935-726-9759

Iran

03/2022 v6.7.0

2008 - 2014

# **Professional Experience**

### Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

**Jibres** Iran (4 years 6 months) 10/2017 - present

- Provide cloud infrastructure to 1,000+ businesses, integrated eCommerce solution with website, app, PoS software, CMS, CRM, accounting software, ticketing system, form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced a new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated a native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

### Founder, CEO, and Software Engineer

**Ermile** Iran (4 years 8 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from Angel investor, spearheaded a 15 member cross-functional team to create a Sarshomar that gained about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

#### Web UI/UX Designer

**Freelancer** (6 years 11 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed, developed 40+ WordPress websites, user experience, communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

### **Computer Lecturer**

**Teacher** 

(15+ years) 06/2006 - (continued)

- Taught 2000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, private classes.
- Created, published tens of hours of unique free web, office video tutorials, which has led to the acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers around the world.

# Volunteer work

#### **DevOps and Front-End Developer**

Khadije Charity Iran (4 years 4 months) 12/2017 - 03/2022

 Developed the website, all the software infrastructure, accelerated fulfill the wishes of 110,000+ people.

#### **Software Solutions for Business Expert**

**WorldSkills Iran** Iran (5 years 4 months) *06/2010 - 08/2015* 

 Tutored, train three talents who won silver, two bronze medals in national competitions; Held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

## Languages

English Fluent C1

**Persian** Native

# **Education**

### M.S. in IT Management

Azad University Tehran, Iran 2015 - 2022

#### **B.S. in Computer Software Engineering**

Azad University Nour, Iran

## Skills

Persistence Micro-Management **Analyst** Presentation Accounting Marketing **Teaching** Sales **Teamwork Decision Making** Database Design **Bug Hunter** Cloud Development Algorithm Microservice **Architecture Data Migration** Maintenance HTML5 **Test Automation** Design Pattern VolP A/B testing pfSense

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, Bash Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML Web Service SOAP, RESTful API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony

Frontend JS Library Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, Angular, jQuery

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Test-driven development - TDD PHPUnit

**CI/CD Container** Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

**Server Configuration Framework, UI** cPanel, DirectAdmin **Software Development Methodology** Scrum, Agile, Kanban **OS** Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi

Microsoft Office Specialist Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma

# **Awards and Honors**

MembershipIranNational Elites Foundation2013The Best Corporate, Tourism WebsiteIran

The Best Corporate, Tourism Website
5th Iran Web Festival

. . . . .

Silver Medal Yazd, Iran

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business

Medallion for Excellence Mashhad, Iran

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

2008

2012

2009